# **Abhinay** Yadav

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

abhinayy48@gmail.com 🔀

7338384951

Bangalore, India

linkedin.com/in/abhinay-yadav-0b4614149 in

portfolio.abhinayy48.repl.co/



Having 1.4 year of experience as a web Developer specializing in front-end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML5, CSS, Typescript, JavaScript, Node.js, Test Driven Development (TDD), MongoDB and Postgres.

# SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React
- Back-end: JavaScript, Typescript, NodeJS
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Version Control: Git-Lab, GitHub, etc.
- Software Development Life Cycle: Waterfall, Agile methodology, Test Driven Development.
- Frameworks and Libraries: Nextjs, Bootstrap, Express, etc.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

# Software Developer

Data Template Infotech Private Limited Mar 2022 - Jun 2023 Attom Data (USA) 2022/0

2022/04 – 2023/6

- **Description**: Attom Cloud Is a Module Of A Attom Data, Which Is The Fastest Way To Access Curated Property Data That Is Matched To Your Need, Easy To Understand, Convenient To Use, And Requires No Additional Hardware.
- Technology Used: React With Typescript, Node.js, Ms-SQL, Microsoft Azure, Agile methodology, etc.
- My Role: Handled The Front-end Part Completely By Myself And Eventually Work On The Back-end.

Calque (USA)

2022/07 - 2022/09

- Description: Calque Offers Lending Solutions. They Buy And Sell Real Estate With Community Banks And Credit Unions. They Are Called Trade-In Mortgages.
- **Technology Used**: React, Python, PostgreSQL, etc.
- My Role: Solve Bugs And Design Feature As Per Wireframes.

## Data Template (Bangalore)

2022/10 - 2022/12

- **Description**: Worked On Internal company Website From Scratch to production.
- Technology Used: React, WordPress, And AWS.
- My Role: Handled The Front-end Part Completely By Myself.

#### Technopro (Japan)

2023/04 - 2023/06

- **Description:** The Techno Pro Group (Japan), A Powerhouse Of The Technology-Focused Staffing And Solution, provides Support For Technical Development And R&D.
- Technology Used: React With D3.js charts.
- My Role: Work With a Team Of three Members Contributed Equally To Assigned Tasks.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Hand-written text recognition system

College project Feb 2021 - Jun 2021

Collected Dataset model for the application and worked on segmentation of the text.

## Internship

Website Design Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 Worked On frontend E-commerce website.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Diploma

BSF Institute of technology, Bangalore Apr 2014 - Jun 2017

Courses - Computer science and Engineering

#### Bechlor of Engineering

CMR Institute of Technolgy Jul 2017 - Sep 2021 Courses – Computer science and Engineering